Carlos González

Senior Software Engineer

Santo Domingo | +1 809-389-0202 | carlosantoniogonzalez@outlook.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/cagonzalezc

Summary

I'm a software developer with experience in a wide scope of development stacks and through the whole process of software development, including analysis, design, architecture, test, and implementation of solutions that support business objectives. With my wide range of experience and skills, I'm quite capable of translating design and requirements into solid scalable applications. I'm always happy to face new challenges that bring out my skills and experience to find solutions to complex problems. I've studied abroad in Spain to sharpen my skills and to get in touch with the market outside of my country. This experience brought me a deeper knowledge of the relationship between business objectives and their implementations of the software development lifecycle.

Work experience

Senior Software Developer

2014 - Now

Dirección General de Impuestos Internos

I'm the senior developer of the development team of the Web Development Department of the general tax direction on the Dominican Republic, I'm in charge of the design and coordination of the development and implementation efforts of the department solutions like:

- Main transactions systems
- Internal management
- software Integration services
- Intergovernmental services

These solutions are used by all the taxpayers in the Dominican Republic. Additionally, I continuously improve the functionality of the company main systems, through the use and enhancements of external APIs as well as handling the backend development of the internal websites.

Web Developer

2017 - 2017

Social Media CRM

Delivered software solutions aimed to enhance a platform created to answer customer concerns about the Metro lines and services in Madrid using the main social media networks (Facebook, Twitter, Whatsapp).

Process Analyst

2014 - 2014

Banco de Reservas

Handle the task of lifting the business processes of the Banco de Reservas in order to do a further rearrangement of those processes creating a factory of processes capable of handling with a high degree of efficiency all the common tasks of the group of processes handled by every new factory created for all the business processes of the company.

Web Developer

2013 - 2014

Excellent Integrity Solutions

In charge of translating the business requirements associated with the SaaS system developed by the company to supply it's own demand of small applications used to interact with the product catalog of a big chain of suppliers in Puerto Rico updating product details, handling payments, and logging and auditing records.

Skills

Back-End Development

- C#.Net
- Model-View-Controler
- Model-View-ViewModel
- API design and development
- MS SQL
- Oracle
- Java SE

Front-End Development

- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Ajax
- Json
- HTML5
- Bootstap
- CSS
- Angular
- ReactJs

Other Skills

- Git
- Agile Methodologies
- Design Patterns
- Project Management
- MS Project
- Software Life Cycle
- MS Windows
- Linux

Languages

- Spanish (native)
- English (bilingual)

Education

Master Software Engineer For the Web

2016 - 2017

Universidad de Alcalá de Henares

I was part of a collaboration program founded by the Ministry of Higher Education Science and Technology (MESCyT).

Barchelor Degree,

2008 - 2014

Universidad Autónoma de Santo Domingo